firsttechcu.com 2008-12-17

# Privacy Policy - First Tech Credit Union

Privacy Policy

First Technology Credit Union is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build user's trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information pratices. This privacy statement covers the site [www.firsttechcu.com](http://www.firsttechcu.com/) and www.1sttech.com.  Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.[](http://www.truste.org/ivalidate.php?url=www.firsttechcu.com&sealid=101)

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should call our contact center at 503.644.4034 or 800.637.0852. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php). TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve your concerns.

**First Tech Credit Union Privacy Policy**  
July, 2005 

This is the joint privacy policy of First Technology Credit Union and our credit union affiliate, TCU Group Services, Inc. which does business as First Tech Financial Services, First Tech Insurance Services, Technology Insurance NW and First Tech Professional Services. Our joint policy describes the applicable member information practices related to each account and service you have with the Credit Union and our financial service affiliate. 

We recognize the importance of our responsibility in protecting our members' nonpublic personal information. We will protect the personal and financial information that you have entrusted to us. We believe that all personal and financial information that you provide to us through any channel constitutes personal information. This includes: information you provide on an application to obtain membership, a loan, credit card or other financial product or service; account balance information, payment history, overdraft history, and credit or debit card purchase information; the fact that you are or have been one of our members; any information collected through a cookie; and any information from your consumer report. 

**1\. Collection of Personal Information**  
When you apply for an account or service from the credit union or our financial service affiliate, we collect and retain nonpublic personal information in order to process your application. We collect the information you provide on your applications and other forms (such as name address, assets, income and employer) and information from a consumer reporting agency (such as your credit history and public records). When you open or use an account or service, we retain personal information you provide in the context of using that product or service, including transaction information. After you sign up for our online services [1stTech Online] our data system records certain online information, including the transactions you conduct online. This data enables us to process and confirm your transactions. When you send us email, we will retain the content of the email, your email address, and our response in order to handle any follow up questions you may have. We also use it to measure how effectively we address your concerns. 

**2\. Use and Sharing of Personal Information**  
In order to provide financial services to you, we share certain information about you with our financial service affiliate and third party service providers. However, we limit any information sharing to the extent necessary to service your account. If we share your information, it is with the goal of bringing you quality services, more choices and greater convenience. Information we may have about former members is generally only shared or disclosed if required to enforce or administer an account or as required by law. 

**3\. Sharing Information with Credit Union Affiliate**  
Our wholly owned financial service affiliate provides financial services including insurance, tax preparation services and auto purchasing. We may share the following information with our affiliate so they can serve you more efficiently: 

  * Member information such as name, address or account number 
  * Account information such as type of loan or share accounts

Because we maintain management control over our financial service affiliate, you can expect our affiliate to maintain the same privacy standards as the Credit Union. You may limit our affiliates from marketing their products or services to you based on the information that we share with them.

**4\. Sharing Information with Third Party Service Providers** In order for us to conduct our operations, including servicing your account or processing your transactions, we need to share information with our service providers. The credit union's service providers include: data processing companies; check, ATM and other payment processing companies; payment networks; loan service providers; insurance companies; collection agencies; and credit reporting agencies. Our financial service affiliates service providers include: data processing companies; insurance companies; payment networks and credit reporting agencies. These service providers act on our behalf and have agreed in writing to keep the information we provide to them confidential. We share the following categories of information with third party service providers depending on the specific services provided: 

  * Member information such as name, address or account number 
  * Account information such as type of accounts, account balances or transaction history
  * Transaction information such as dates, amounts, locations and type of transaction

The Credit Union and affiliate does not sell or share any member information with nonaffiliated third party marketers offering their products and services. 

**4 a. Sharing Information with Third Party Service Providers  
** While we may offer valuable financial products and services of our affiliate or third parties, we control the member information used to make such offers. We currently offer members insurance products offered by American Express Property Casualty, Hartford Accidental Death & Dismemberment Insurance, and Capstone Group, Long Term Care Specialist. You may tell us not to offer these services to you as explained in the Opt Out section of this notice.

**5\. Sharing Information as Legally Required or Permitted**  
We may share any nonpublic personal information of yours in response to a lawful request issued by a court, government agency, or regulatory authority or as permitted by law in order to administer or enforce your account. We may also share our experience information about you with credit bureaus. Our reporting to credit bureaus is governed by the Fair Credit Reporting Act, which affords you the right to make sure that your credit bureau reports are accurate. 

**6\. Accuracy of Personal Information**  
We will exercise reasonable procedures in order to assure the accuracy of our records and your personal information. Inaccurate information, when brought to our attention, is corrected as promptly as possible. If you have any questions regarding the accuracy of your personal information, please call a Credit Union representative, or contact us at [memberservice@firsttechcu.com ](mailto:memberservice@firsttechcu.com). We will investigate your issue and update your records as needed. We request that you keep your personal information as current as possible so that you may get the maximum benefit from the Credit Union. In particular, please make sure that you inform us of your email address changes so that we may communicate with you. 

**7\. Protection of Personal Information**  
We use multiple levels of security, beginning with your browser and ending with a secure operating system that acts as a virtual information vault inside the Credit Union. Information we receive via online applications is secure and requires industry standard Secure Socket Layer encrypted browsers. Protecting your privacy is an ongoing process. We restrict access to nonpublic personal information about you to those employees who need to know that information to provide products or services to you. We will continue to review the measures we take to safeguard your personal information. These reviews will result in new measures to protect member records, as we make changes to our information security practices and other internal control systems to take advantage of new technology. 

**8\. Privacy Related Complaints**  
If you believe that First Tech Credit Union or its financial services affiliate has not complied with this Privacy Policy with respect to your personal information, you may write the First Tech Privacy Officer at: Privacy Officer, First Tech Credit Union, PO Box 2100, Beaverton, OR 97075, email to [privacy@firsttechcu.com](mailto:privacy@firsttechcu.com) or deliver your letter to the main branch located at 3555 SW 153rd, Beaverton, OR. Please describe in your letter in as much detail as possible the ways you believe that the policy has not been complied with. We will investigate each issue promptly. 

**9\. Notification of Changes**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our website so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of mail or an electronic notification service. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. 

**10\. Use of Cookies**  
When you visit [www.firsttechcu.com](http://www.firsttechcu.com/), you can surf the public site anonymously and access important information without revealing your identity. In order to improve our site, we use "cookies" to track how our site is being used. Our web servers automatically log the IP/Internet address of your computer. The cookie will not request, require, or collect personal identifying information and you remain anonymous. The cookie identified as Hitbox.com is used to better record audience behavior. It creates profiles based on the path you take while on our site and will not associate with personal identifying information. The information from the Hitbox cookie is used by First Tech Credit Union and is not shared with any third parties. When you engage in certain activities on our site, such as home banking, or application for other online services, the Credit Union may ask you to provide certain information about yourself by filling out and submitting an online form. It is completely optional for you to engage in these activities. 

Cookies are also used by 1sttech Online Banking during a login session for security purposes. The secure cookie may contain the following information in an encrypted format: globally unique identifier (GUID), your name, account number, home phone, work phone and email address. We use "strong" encryption (128 bit key length or higher) to protect the data within this cookie and we change the encryption keys regularly. This secure cookie is generated when you arrive and is discarded when you leave our secure site. This is a memory only cookie, which means that when you close the browser, the cookie is deleted. These cookies are time sensitive and will expire after a period of time. Once expired, the secure cookie is no longer usable. This is designed to increase your security while using 1sttech Online Banking. This secure cookie is for First Tech only and we do not share this encryption key with any 3rd party vendors. 

**11\. Links**  
This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that First Tech Credit Union is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site. Some of the links from our site will take you off the firsttechcu.com site to a "co-branded" site where you will see the First Tech logo as well as the logo of another service provider. The following links to sites are co-branded: Taleo, Advanced Automation Solutions, Sharebuilder, eVision Online Investing, CUSO Financial Services, Online Banking, Liberty Check ordering, NW Corp Check Images, Umonitor, eCom, Experion Systems, Advocar and CUDL. Any information you provide is collected by the service provider and you are encouraged to read the privacy statement of that provider. 

We also have links from firsttechcu.com to "fully branded" service provider sites. As you view information on a fully branded site you will see a change in the URL but the pages appear as First Tech Credit Union's and the service provider is not identified. All information collected on fully branded sites is used by First Tech Credit Union only and is not shared or used for any purpose other than processing your application and providing the requested service. Fully branded sites include: online mortgage applications, check printing, e-notices, share draft images, funds transfer service and aggregation.

**12\. First Tech Credit Union does not sell or share your information with outside third party marketers.  
** As described in this policy, we may share your information within the First Tech family of affiliates. By sharing this information, we can better understand your financial needs and send you information about products and services that you may not otherwise know about. You may limit the sharing of information within the First Tech affiliates at any time. You may also limit the type of marketing material First Tech and its affiliates send you as explained below:

  * You do not want our affiliates to market their products or services to you based on the information that we share with them.
  * You do not want offers of products by third parties
  * You do not want to be contacted with offers by mail.
  * You do not want to be contacted with offers by email.
  * You do not want to be contacted with offers by telephone.

To opt out, please call:   
503.644.4034 or 1.800.637.0852  
Hours: M - F 8am - 6pm, Sat 10am - 2pm  
Or click here to complete an electronic opt-out form.

This opt-out applies only to the accounts you provide, accounts opened after this opt-out will require their own opt-out instructions.

Your opt-out choices will remain in effect until you notify us otherwise.
